[
    {
        "question": "Which module gives control of the CPU to the process selected by the short-term scheduler?",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "interrupt",
            "scheduler",
            "none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "dispatcher",
        "explanation": "None."
    },
    {
        "question": "The processes that are residing in main memory and are ready and waiting to execute are kept on a list called _____________",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "job queue",
            "execution queue",
            "process queue"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "ready queue",
        "explanation": "None."
    },
    {
        "question": "The interval from the time of submission of a process to the time of completion is termed as ____________",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "waiting time",
            "response time",
            "throughput"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "turnaround time",
        "explanation": "None."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which scheduling algorithm allocates the CPU first to the process that requests the CPU first?",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "shortest job scheduling",
            "priority scheduling",
            "none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "first-come, first-served scheduling",
        "explanation": "None."
    },
    {
        "question": "In priority scheduling algorithm ____________",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "CPU is allocated to the process with lowest priority",
            "Equal priority processes can not be scheduled",
            "None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "CPU is allocated to the process with highest priority",
        "explanation": "None."
    },
    {
        "question": "In priority scheduling algorithm, when a process arrives at the ready queue, its priority is compared with the priority of ____________",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "all process",
            "parent process",
            "init process"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "currently running process",
        "explanation": "None."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which algorithm is defined in Time quantum?",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "shortest job scheduling algorithm",
            "priority scheduling algorithm",
            "multilevel queue scheduling algorithm"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "round robin scheduling algorithm",
        "explanation": "None."
    },
    {
        "question": "Process are classified into different groups in ____________",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "shortest job scheduling algorithm",
            "round robin scheduling algorithm",
            "priority scheduling algorithm"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "multilevel queue scheduling algorithm",
        "explanation": "None."
    },
    {
        "question": "In multilevel feedback scheduling algorithm ____________",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "classification of ready queue is permanent",
            "processes are not classified into groups",
            "none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a process can move to a different classified ready queue",
        "explanation": "None."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following can not be scheduled by the kernel?",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "kernel level thread",
            "process",
            "none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "user level thread",
        "explanation": "User level threads are managed by thread library and the kernel is unaware of them."
    }
]